<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Torleif Nielsen</title>
    <link>http://torleif.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Torleif Nielsen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 12:22:59 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://torleif.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduated!</title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/post/graduated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 12:22:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/post/graduated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I graduated~!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORCA</title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/project/orca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 20:29:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/project/orca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online Resource &amp;amp; Content Administrator&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 13:00:29 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaiapuni</title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/project/kaiapuni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 01:14:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/project/kaiapuni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An i18n enabled online platform for creating, distributing, and scoring standardized exams for culturally diverse testing practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Tor and I am a mostly self-trained Software Developer hailing from Honolulu, and I develop primarily for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember I have loved to build things, and every finished project just spawned new ideas to pursue. If I have to attribute any one thing to my start in programming, I would say it was Legos. As a kid I had the luxury of more Legos than I knew what to do with, and after Legos I had &amp;ldquo;Zometools&amp;rdquo;, which let me build even stranger and more complex things. Not long after that I received one of the first Lego Mindstorms kits and began learning how to program the yellow brick to power my strange creations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 16 years old I found a book on Lisp and stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Ruby tutorials and I just started playing with languages. I very quickly realized I had stumbled upon a means of building something that could be massive in scale without littering the floor with plastic caltrops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set about scouring the internet for all kinds of resources from forum posts and blogs to video tutorials. Following that I found interest in conference talk recordings and diving into GitHub repositories. After a couple of years playing with Ruby, Python, JavaScript, PHP, and C, I decided I wanted to build for the platforms I used the most&amp;ndash; the web browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to reinforce my HTML knowledge and pick up web frameworks like Rails, Drupal, WordPress, and later Meteor. I realized around then that I had incurred a massive debt to open source communities. I resolved at that point to pursue a degree in a Computer related field and further develop my skills so that I can give back to open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short I am addicted to learning and building new things, and sharing everything I learn with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-am-usually-up-to&#34;&gt;What I am usually up to&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from UH Computer Science program with a B.S. in Computer Science, and left my position as a Web Programmer for the Distance Course Design &amp;amp; Consulting group at UH Manoa. When school was in session I was easily found amongst the computer related clubs on campus and now I hang out in chat channels all over the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I could find the time, I taught a variety of topics about programming and software engineering to fellow students. I have taught high school and college students how to develop with git, fundamental programming concepts, program design, test-driven and behavior-driven development, and some topics relating to specific programming languages (e.g. Functional vs OO programming).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently since graduating I have taken to contributing more to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/torleif-nielsen&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and writing for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gitbook.com/@torleif-nielsen/&#34;&gt;GitBook&lt;/a&gt; platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://torleif.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://torleif.io/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>